Sex. Clothes. Popularity. Is there a problem here?
Clueless is a comedy, romance film directed by Amy Heckerling.
Shallow, rich and socially successful Cher is at the top of
her Beverly Hills high school's pecking scale.
Seeing herself as a matchmaker, Cher first coaxes
two teachers into dating each other.
Emboldened by her success, she decides to give
hopelessly klutzy new student Tai a makeover.
When Tai becomes more popular than she is, Cher realizes that her disapproving
ex-stepbrother was right about how misguided she was -- and falls for him.
Cher, played by Alicia Silverstone.
Dionne, played by Stacey Dash.
Tai, played by Brittany Murphy.
Josh, played by Paul Rudd.
Murray, played by Donald Faison.
Amber, played by Elisa Donovan.
Clueless is a 1995 American coming-of-age teen comedy film
written and directed by Amy Heckerling.
It stars Alicia Silverstone, and was produced by
Scott Rudin and Robert Lawrence.
The film is a loose adaptation of Jane Austen's 1815 novel Emma.
The plot centers on a beautiful, popular, wealthy high
school student who wants to do "good deeds".
She befriends a newcomer and decides to give her a makeover while playing
matchmaker for her teachers and examining her own existence.
Clueless was filmed in Southern California over a 40-day schedule.
Heckerling studied Beverly Hills High School students to understand how teenagers in
the 1990s talked and learned some appropriate slang terms from them.
Clueless was released by Paramount Pictures on July 19, 1995.
The film grossed $88 million worldwide, and was further
successful in the home video market.
It received positive reviews from critics and is considered
to be one of the best teen films of all time.
Clueless has developed a cult following and has a continuing legacy.
The film was followed by a spin-off television sitcom and series of books.
The film explores themes of puberty, high school, based on
novel or book, make a match, spoiled child.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.